城堡石娱乐公司  出   品 .
与尼尔森娱乐公司 共同奉献 .
罗伯?莱纳 电影作品 .
[TYPING]
[DINGS]
全书完
无  题  保罗?谢尔登著
Still got it.
照样命中
[SHOTGUN  PLAYING ON CAR RADIO]
片名  米瑟丽  台译：颤栗游戏 / 港译：危情十日  .
主演  詹姆斯?凯恩 .
? I said, Shotgun
主演  凯西?贝茨 因本片获得 第63届奥斯卡金像奖最佳女主角  .
? Shoot 'em for he runs now
? Do the jerk baby
? Do the jerk now
? Hey
? Put on your red dress
? And then you go downtown now
? I said buy yourself a shotgun now
? We're gonna break it down baby now
? We're gonna load it up baby now
? And then you shoot him for he runs now
? I said, Shotgun
? Shoot 'em for he runs now
? Do the jerk baby
? Do the jerk now
? Hey
? Put on your high heels shoes
? I said we're goin' down here listen to 'em play blues
? We're gonna dig potatoes
? We're gonna pick tomatoes
本片依据斯蒂芬?金 小说《Misery》改编 .
? I said, Shotgun
? Shoot 'em for he runs now
? Do the jerk baby
? Do the jerk now
编 剧 威廉姆?高德曼 .
? Hey
? I said it's Twine Time
[TIRES SCREECHING]
制 片 安德鲁?沙因曼 罗伯?莱纳 .
导 演 罗伯?莱纳 .
MARCIA: What's that?
那是什么?
An old friend.
老朋友
I was rummaging through a closet,
我翻衣橱时找到了它
and it was just sitting there.
It's nice, Paul.
不错,保罗,它很有特点
It's got character.
When I wrote my first book, I used to carry it around in this
我写完第一本书时 带着它到处去找出版商
while I was looking for a publisher.
I was a writer then. You're still a writer.
- 那时我是个作家 - 你现在还是
I haven't been a writer since I got in the Misery business.
写米瑟丽系列之后 我就不再是了
本字幕仅供学习交流 严禁用于商业用途 .
Not a bad business.
但那是不错的生意呀 而这生意仍会持续兴旺
And it would still be growing, too.
The first printing for  Misery's Child
初版的《米瑟丽的童年》 是最成功的,超过一百万册
was the most ever, over a million.
Marcia, please.
玛西娅,别提了
Misery Chastain put braces on your daughter's teeth
米瑟丽系列小说养活你的女儿 供她念大学
and is putting her through college,
bought you two houses and floor seats to the Knicks.
你买了两幢房子 看球赛坐在好座位
And what thanks does she get?
你感谢她了吗? 你却杀了她
You go and kill her.
I never meant for it to become my life.
我从没想过它 会成为我的生命
And if I hadn't gotten rid of her now,
若我现在还不摆脱她 就只能永远受她的役使了
I'd have ended up writing her forever.
Now I'm leaving for Colorado to try to finish the new book.
我去科罗拉多,设法完成新书
If I can make this work,
若我能够做到 那么我墓碑上就有东西可写了
I might just have something I want on my tombstone.
[GASPING]
ANNIE: I'm your number one fan.
我是你的头号书迷
There's nothing to worry about.
没什么可担心的
You're gonna be just fine.
你正在好起来 我会好好照顾你的
I'll take good care of you.
I'm your number one fan.
我是你的头号书迷
Where am I?
这是哪儿?
We're just outside Silver Creek.
我们是在银溪镇外
How long?
多久了?
You've been here two days.
你在这里两天了,你会没事的
You're gonna be okay.
My name is Annie Wilkes.
我叫安妮?威尔斯
My number one fan.
我的头号书迷
Yes. That's right.
对了,对极了,我也是护士
I'm also a nurse.
Here. Take these.
这里,含着
含着
Here.
给
What are they?
- 这是什么? - 这是纳沃富,是止痛药
They're called Novril. They're for your pain.
Thank you.
谢谢
How come I'm not in a hospital?
怎么我不在医院?
The blizzard was too strong.
暴风雪太厉害了,我不能冒险
I couldn't risk trying to get you there.
I tried calling, but the phone lines are down.
我试着打电话,但线路不通
[GROANS]
你不能劳累,必须要充分休息
You mustn't tire yourself.
You've gotta rest.
You almost died.
你差一点就死了
Open wide.
张开嘴巴啊
Your legs just sing grand opera when you move, don't they?
你一动,双腿就痛的要命是吗?
It's not gonna hurt forever, Paul. I promise you.
那会好起来的,保罗 我保证
Will I be able to walk?
我还可以走路吗?
Of course you will.
当然,你可以的
And your arm will be fine, too.
你的手臂也会没事儿
Your shoulder was pretty badly dislocated.
你肩膀脱臼得很严重
It was a little stubborn, but I finally popped it back in.
有点棘手,但最后 我还是把它归位了
What I'm most proud of is the work I did on those legs.
我对你的腿所做的,才叫我骄傲
Considering what I had around the house,
以我这里的现有条件 我不认为哪个医生会做得更好
I don't think there's a doctor who could have done any better.
It's not nearly as bad as it looks.
它不像看起来那么严重
You have a compound fracture of the tibia in both legs,
但你双腿的胫骨有多处骨折
and the fibula in the right leg is fractured, too.
右腿的腓骨也有骨折
I could hear the bones moving,
我可以听到骨头在移动
so it's best for your legs to remain immobile.
因此你的腿最好别动
And as soon as the roads open, I'll take you to a hospital.
只要路面重开,我会带你去医院
In the meantime, you've got a lot of recovering to do,
目前你还要好好休养康复
and I consider it an honor that you'll do it in my home.
你待在我家,我认为是我的光荣
This is Marcia Sindell, I'm calling from New York City.
我是玛西娅?辛德尔 从纽约打来的
I'd like to speak to the Silver Creek Chief of Police or Sheriff.
想找银溪镇警署 警察或是警长
BUSTER: Which one of them do you want?
- 你想找他们中的哪位? - 谁有空就找谁
Whichever one's not busy.
Well, I'm pretty sure they're both not busy, Miss Sindell,
我确信他们俩都有空 辛德尔小姐,因为都是我
since they're both me.
I also happen to be President of
我碰巧也是警察互助会的主任
the Policeman's Benefit Association,
Chairman of the Patrolman's Retirement Fund,
巡警退休基金的主管
and if you need a good fishing guide, you could do a lot worse.
如果你要找高超的钓鱼向导 情况就不太妙了
Call me Buster, everybody does.
叫我老兄吧,大家都是这样
What can I do for you?
我可以为你做什么?
I'm a literary agent, and I...
我是作家经纪人,我… 打电话给你,我感到可笑
I feel like a fool calling you,
but I think one of my clients, Paul Sheldon,
但我认为有一位客户 保罗?谢尔登,可能遇到了麻烦
might be in some kind of trouble.
You mean Paul Sheldon the writer? Uh-huh.
你是说作家保罗?谢尔登吗?
He's your client, huh? Yes, he is.
- 他是你的客户?是吗 - 是的,他是
Everybody sure likes those  Misery books.
大家都很喜欢他的米瑟丽小说
Yeah.
对
I'm sure you know that, uh, Paul's been coming
我相信你知道,保罗多年来 都到银溪旅馆…
to the Silver Creek Lodge for years to finish his books.
完成写作
I understand he's been up here the last six weeks.
我知道,他过去六个星期 一直都在这里
Well, not quite.
好吧,不太确定 我打电话过去,他们…
I just called there and they...
They said he checked out last Tuesday.
他们说他上星期二已退房 不是有点奇怪吗?
Isn't that a little strange?
Oh, I don't know. Does he usually phone you
我不晓得,他通常离开旅馆前 是否都会打电话给你?
before he checks out of a hotel?
No. No, of course not.
不,当然不,只是 他的女儿也没有他的消息
It's just that his daughter hasn't heard from him,
and, uh, when he has a new book coming out, he usually keeps in touch.
他有新书推出时,一般会保持联络
So when there wasn't any word from him, I...
现在,他没有任何音讯,我…
You think he might be missing, huh?
你认为他可能失踪了?是吧
[SIGHING] I hate that I made this call.
我本不想打电话的,说我笨蛋吧
Tell me I'm being silly.
Oh, a little overprotective maybe,
只是稍微有点过于担心,但是 告诉你,我也会这样做
but tell you what I'll do.
Nothing's been reported out here,
这儿没有收到报告
but I'll put his name through our system,
但我会把他的名字登记在案
and if anything turns up, I'll call you right back.
有了任何发现,我肯定通知你
I'd appreciate that. Thanks a lot.
非常感激,谢谢
Goodbye, Miss Sindell.
再见辛德尔小姐
We got a phone call? Busy morning.
通电话啊?今早挺忙的
Yeah. Work, work, work.
对,工作,工作,工作
Virginia, when was that blizzard?
维吉尼娅,上次的暴风雪是哪天?
Last Tuesday. Why?
上星期二,怎么了?
No reason.
没什么
I guess it was kind of a miracle, you finding me.
我看你找到我,是个奇迹
No, it wasn't a miracle at all.
不,一点都不是奇迹
In a way, I was following you.
- 可以说我是跟踪你的 - 跟踪我?
You were following me?
好吧,你住在银溪镇 对我来说不是秘密
Well, it wasn't any secret to me
you were staying at the Silver Creek,
seeing as how I'm your number one fan and all.
我是你的头号书迷
Some nights I'd just tool on down there and sit outside
有时晚上我会前去那儿 坐在外面
and look up at the light in your cabin,
望着你小屋的灯光
and I'd try to imagine what was going on
我会想象世界上最伟大的作家 在房间里做什么呐
in the room of the world's greatest writer.
Say the last part again. I didn't hear you.
- 再说说,我没听清 - 现在别动
Don't move now.
I wouldn't wanna hurt this neck.
我不想割破你的脖子
Well, the other afternoon,
好吧,那天下午 我在回家路上
I was on my way home,
and there you were, leaving the lodge.
而你,离开了旅馆
And I wondered why a literary genius would go for a drive
我寻思这位文学天才为什么 在暴风雪来到时开车外出
when there was a big storm coming.
I didn't know there was a big storm coming.
我不知道暴风雪将临
Well, lucky for you I did.
算你走运,我知道 而我也真是运气好的不得了
Lucky for me, too.
'Cause now you're alive and you can write more books.
那是因为你,你还活着 你还能写更多的书
Oh, Paul, I've read everything of yours.
哦保罗,我看过你所有的书
But the  Misery novels.
米瑟丽小说系列 我全都用心读过,全部八本儿
I know them all by heart. All eight of them.
I love them so.
我超喜欢
You're very kind.
- 你非常客气    - 你真了不起
And you're very brilliant.
Like a baby.
像个小宝宝,好了
All done.
谢谢你
Thank you.
When do you think the phone lines will be up?
你觉得电话何时会正常? 我要打电话给女儿
I have to call my daughter, and I'd like to call my agent in New York
还要告诉纽约的经纪人 让他们知道我还活着
and let her know I'm still breathing.
It shouldn't be too much longer now.
应该是不会太久了
Once the roads are opened, the phone lines will be up in no time.
如果路面重开 电话线路很快就会通了
If you give me their numbers, I'll keep trying them for you.
把她们的号码给我 我试着替你打
Thank you.
谢谢
Could I ask you a favor?
我可以向你提一个请求吗?
I noticed in your case there is a new Paul Sheldon book,
我注意到皮包里 有你的新书,那么
and I wondered if maybe...
不知道可不可以…
You wanna read it?
- 你想看吗? - 那,若你不介意的话
Well, if you wouldn't mind.
Well, I do have a very hard and fast rule
我对于谁能优先阅读初稿 有着很严格的规定
as to who reads my stuff at this early stage.
Only my editor, my agent,
惟有编辑、经纪人…
and anybody that saves me from freezing to death in a car wreck.
以及在暴风雪中的汽车里 救出我的人,才可以
You'll never realize what a rare treat you've given me.
啊哟,你不知道你给了我 多么难得的待遇啊
Boy, it's like clockwork, the way your pain comes.
小弟,你的痛苦 像上了发条似的按时发作
I'll get you your Novril, Paul.
我给你拿止痛药,保罗
Forgive me for prattling away and making you feel all oogy.
原谅我不停地嗦 让你觉得很无聊
What's your new book called?
你的新书叫什么名字?
I don't have a title yet.
我还没命名
What's it about?
是写什么的?
I don't know.
我不太明确
I know it sounds crazy, but I haven't
我知道这听起来不可思议
written anything but  Misery for so long.
但我一直没写过别的 总是在写米瑟丽
Why don't you read it?
你何不看看,…告诉我你觉得怎样
And you can tell me what you think it's about.
Maybe you can come up with a title.
也许你可以想出一个书名
Like I could do that.
就好像我能做到一样!
银溪旅馆
LIBBY: Nothing unusual about Mr. Sheldon's leaving, Buster.
银溪旅馆  谢尔登先生离开时没有异常,老兄
You can tell by the champagne.
- 从他点的香槟就可以看出 - 也许你能…
Maybe you can, Libby.
See, he always orders a bottle of Dom Perignon
不,你看,他总会要一瓶香槟 准备离开
when he's ready to go.
Then he pays up and he's out the door.
付帐以后就走了
No long-distance phone calls or Federal Express packages?
没有打长途电话,或者快递包裹?
Anything out of the ordinary?
或者任何异常的地方?
I don't think Mr. Sheldon likes for things to be out of the ordinary.
不,谢尔登先生不喜欢与众不同
Considering who he is, and all famous and all,
他是非常有名的作家
he doesn't put on airs.
可他从不摆架子
Drives up from New York in the same car each time.
每次都开同一辆车从纽约来 是65年的野马汽车
A '65 Mustang. Says it helps him to think.
说有助于他思考
He's always been a good guest.
他一直是个好客人
Never makes a noise. Never bothers a soul.
从不吵嚷,也不打扰别人
I sure hope nothing's happened to him.
- 我希望他不会有事 - 我也一样
So do I.
I bet that old Mustang is pulling into New York right now.
我相信车子现在已驶进纽约
I'm sure you're right. Thanks, Libby.
相信会的,谢谢
My pleasure.
别客气
I know I'm only 40 pages into your book, but...
我只看了40页,但是…
But what?
但是什么?
Nothing.
没什么
No, no, no. What is it?
别,它怎么样?
It's ridiculous.
嗯,那不合情理
Who am I to make a criticism to someone like you?
我是谁,竟然批评你这样的作家?
It's all right, I can take it.
没关系,我可以接受
Well, it's brilliantly written.
写的很出色,你的作品全都很精彩
But then everything you write is brilliant.
Pretty rough stuff, huh?
是很粗俗吧?
The swearing, Paul.
是骂骂咧咧,保罗
There, I said it.
那里边,我说了
Yeah. The profanity bothers you.
对,你不喜欢污言秽语
It has no nobility.
它不高贵
These are slum kids.
那些都是贫民窟孩子 我以前也是贫民窟孩子
I was a slum kid.
Everybody talks like that.
- 那里每个人都这样说话 - 才不是
They do not!
What do you think I say when I go to the feed store in town?
你说我到镇上去,该怎么说?
"Now, Wally, give me a bag of that f-ing pig feed
「给我来一袋他妈的猪饲料」
"and 10 pounds of that bitchly cow corn!"
「十磅那狗娘养的牛饲料」
And--And the bank, do I tell Mrs. Bollinger,
在银行,我会对出纳布尔太太说
"Here's one big bastard of a check,
「这是那婊子养的支票 把你那些混帐的钱给我」
"give me some of your Christing money"?
There! Look, there!
就是这样 你看看,你叫我这样?
See what you made me do?
Oh, Paul, I'm sorry.
噢保罗,我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
我真抱歉
Sometimes I get so worked up.
有时候我是很冲动 你能原谅我吗?
Can you ever forgive me?
It's fine.
没关系
I love you, Paul.
我爱你,保罗
Your mind, your creativity.
你的想法 我的意思是你的创造力
That's-- That's all I meant.
Well, this sure is fun.
好吧,这的确很有趣
Virginia, when you're in this car,
维吉尼娅,在这车上 你不是我的老婆,是副手
you're not my wife, you're my deputy.
Well, this deputy'd rather be home
对呀,这副手宁愿待在家里 跟警长裹在一条被子里
under the covers with the Sheriff.
Stop. What?
- 停     - 怎么啦?
Stop! What?
- 停车     - 为什么?
See that broken limb?
看见折断的树枝吗?
Could've been the weight of the snow.
可能是雪太重压断的
Yeah, could've been a rotten branch, could've been the wind.
是吗?可能是树枝枯萎 也可能风吹断了
Could've been a lot of things.
可能有各种原因
[GRUNTS]
[EXCLAIMS]
该死
Need some help?
要帮忙吗?
No, I'm enjoying myself! Thank you.
不,我不过是自言自语 谢谢你
You really think Sheldon's out there?
你真认为谢尔登会在那边?
I hope not.
希望不会,要不然,他就没命了
If he is, he's dead.
Let's go to the newspaper office.
我们去报社吧
Oh, I hope I didn't wake you.
我希望我没有吵醒你
No, it's fine.
没有,没关系
Look what I got.
米瑟丽的童年 .  看我买了什么,商店里有 保罗.有好大一堆呐
They had it at the store, Paul.
There was a whole batch of them there.
And as soon as I saw it, I slammed my money down.
我一看见马上就扑过去 付了钱,买到第一本
I got the first copy.
Then the roads are open.
- 那么路面是重开了 - 嗯,只有去镇上的路通了
Well, the one to town is, but that's about it.
I called the hospital and I talked to the head orthopedic surgeon,
我打电话到医院 给首席骨科医生谈过
and I told him who you were and what had happened.
我告诉他你是谁,出了什么事
And he said as long as there's no infection, you're not in any danger.
他说只要没有发炎 你没有任何危险
And as soon as the road to the hospital is open,
一旦通往医院的路重开 他们就会为你派救护车来
they'll send an ambulance for you.
The phone's working?
电话可以用了吗?
Well, mine's still out,
我的仍然打不通 镇上的电话可以用了
but the ones in town were working just fine.
I called that agent of yours.
我打电话给你的经纪人了
Oh, Paul, I peeked at the very beginning.
保罗,我刚看了书的开头
What a wonderful first page.
第一页真是太棒了
Just to read the name, Misery Chastain...
- 一看到米瑟丽的名字 - 我的女儿一定不高兴
My daughter's gotta be going nuts.
...it's like a visit from my oldest, dearest friend.
就像老朋友久别重逢…
I'm supposed to be home for her birthday.
我本该回到家 为她庆祝生日,就是今天
It's today.
The agent said she would tell her you were okay,
经纪人说会告诉她,你放心
but I'm afraid you'll have to wait till tomorrow
如果你要亲自跟她说 我怕你就不得不等到明天了
if you wanna talk to her yourself.
Oh, Paul, what a poet you are.
哦保罗…,你真是一个诗人
I made you my specialty.
我给你做了我的拿手菜 威尔斯炒蛋
Scrambled eggs a la Wilkes.
And I'm on page 75.
我看到第75页了
I guess that means it's okay.
我看还可以吧
No.
不
No, it isn't. It's...
不,它不是,它是…
Oh, pooh. I can't think of any words.
得了吧,我想不出来了
Would "great" be insulting?
说「太棒了」,会是侮辱吗?
I can live with "great."
我可以接受这个太棒了
No.
不,它不仅是太棒了,而是…
It's not just great,
it's perfect.
完美的
A perfect, perfect thing.
一件完美,完美的东西
[SNORTING]
I thought it was time you two should meet.
我觉得你们两个现在该见面了
Paul, say hello to my favorite beast in the whole world.
噢!保罗,跟我在世界上 最喜欢的动物,打个招呼吧
My sow, Misery.
是我的母猪米瑟丽
Misery?
米瑟丽?
Yes. I told you I was your number one fan.
对呀,我说过我是你的头号书迷
Yeah, I'm, uh, starting to believe you.
是啊,我是…,我开始相信了
This farm was kind of dreary,
这农场以前很乏味 只有几头母牛小鸡和我
what with just a few cows and chickens and me.
But when I got Misery here, everything changed.
但是当我有了米瑟丽 一切都改变了
She just makes me smile so.
她常常让我欢笑
She's a fine, um, pig, is what she is.
她是一头好猪
她的确是
I'm on page 300 now, Paul.
我看到第300页了,保罗
And it's better than perfect. It's divine.
它比完美还要更好,是神圣!
What's the ceiling that dago painted?
那些南欧人在天花板上 画的是什么?
The Sistine Chapel.
- 西斯廷教堂吗? - 对啦!
Yeah! That and  Misery's Child,
是呀!那个教堂和米瑟丽的童年
those are the only two divine things ever in this world.
是世界上仅有的两个 最神圣的东西!
[IMITATING MISERY SNORTING]
When my husband left me, I wasn't prepared.
丈夫离开我时,我毫无准备
It wasn't an easy time.
那段日子很难熬
For a while, I thought I might go crazy.
有一阵子,我以为我会发疯
I know how that can be.
我知道那种心情
I don't know about you,
我不晓得你,怎样熬过去
but what I did to get through it was I dove into work.
我一头扎进工作里
Days, nights.
白天,黑夜
Night shifts can be lonely at a hospital.
在医院值夜班是很寂寞的
I did a lot of reading.
我看了许多书
That was when I first discovered Misery.
那是我第一次发现了米瑟丽
She made me so happy.
她让我如此快乐 使我忘了我所有的问题
She made me forget all my problems.
Of course, I suppose, you had a little something to do with that, too.
当然,我认为也许有一些些 是你的原因
Yeah, well...
是吗,这个…
I just kept reading them over and over.
我不断地重复细看
I've only got two chapters to go in this one,
只剩下两章,我看下去
and I know when I finish, I'll just turn right to the first page
我知道,我看完后会翻到第一页… 再从头开始看一遍
and start reading it all over again.
I'm...
我…
Done? Yeah.
- 完了?    - 是的
No problem.
没问题
Thanks.
谢谢
Don't get me wrong. I'm not against marriage per se,
别误会我,我不是反对婚姻,可是…
but it'd take a pretty special guy
要有一个非常特殊的家伙 才能让我再次想要结婚
to make me wanna walk down that aisle again.
Yeah, it's, uh, not something you should enter into lightly.
对,此事不可轻率
It boils down to respect.
主要的是尊重
People just don't respect the institution of marriage anymore.
人们如今不再尊重婚姻
They have no sense of real commitment.
也不再知道什么真正的承诺
Well, I'd love to stay here and chat,
这个…
but I'm right at the end and I gotta find out what happens.
嗯,我很想留下跟你聊
可我快要看完了,而且 我必须得知道结局是什么
[DOOR CLOSING]
[DOOR OPENING]
You.
你…
You dirty bird.
你…这个卑鄙的东西 你怎么能这样?
How could you?
She can't be dead.
她不能死! 米瑟丽不能死!
Misery Chastain cannot be dead.
Annie, in 1871, women often died in childbirth.
安妮,在1871年 女人往往因难产而死
But her spirit is the important thing,
她的精神是最重要的 米瑟丽的精神仍然存在
and Misery's spirit is still alive.
I don't want her spirit!
我才不要她的精神! 我要她活着!
I want her!
And you murdered her!
你杀了她!
No. I didn't.
不
Who did?
我没有
No one.
谁干的?
She died. She just slipped away.
没有谁,她死了,只是在消失
"Slipped away"?
消失?
She didn't just slip away! You did it!
她不会消失!是你干的!
You did it! You did it!
你干的!你干的!
是你干的!你干的!
You murdered my Misery!
- 你干的!你杀了我的米瑟丽 - 安妮,安妮…
Annie! Annie!
I thought you were good, Paul, but you're not good.
我还以为你是好人,保罗
但是你不是,你只是又一个 说谎的卑鄙家伙
You're just another lying, old dirty birdie,
and I don't think I better be around you for a while.
我觉得我不在你身边 会更要好一些
And don't even think about anybody coming for you.
别指望有人会来找你 不会有医生
Not the doctors, not your agent, not your family
不会有经纪人 也不会有你的家人
because I never called them.
我压根就没有打电话给他们
Nobody knows you're here.
没人知道你在这里
And you better hope nothing happens to me.
你最好希望 我别出什么事儿
Because if I die, you die.
因为如果我死了,你也只有死
[DOOR SLAMMING SHUT]
[CAR ENGINE STARTING]
[THUDDING]
[SCREAMS]
BUSTER: No, Miss Sindell, there's no point in coming up here now.
不,辛德尔小姐 你现在来这儿没有用
Everything that can be done is.
所有能做的,我们都作了
Yes, we're working close with the State Police
是的,我们正在和州警局密切合作 也已通知了联邦调查局
and the FBI's been informed.
Right. Right.
好的,好的… 我们一有消息就马上通知你
As soon as we know anything, we'll let you know.
No bother at all.
一点也不麻烦,随时来电话 再见,辛德尔小姐
Call anytime. Goodbye, Miss Sindell.
All right. Well, I sure appreciate it.
好的,好吧,我非常感谢,谢谢你
Thank you.
According to the check on Sheldon's credit charges,
根据谢尔登的信用卡记录 离开银溪之后就再也没有用过
there's nothing after the Silver Creek.
And no calls about the article either.
也没有关于书稿的电话
You poor, dear thing.
你这可怜的坏东西
What are you doing on the floor?
你在地板上干嘛?
It's all my fault.
都是我不好
If I'd had a proper hospital bed, this never would've happened.
要是有一张医院病床 这就再不会发生了
Here, let me help you back in.
来,我扶你回床上去
I know this hurts, but it will only take a few seconds.
我知道会很痛,但只是一下
[GROANING] Upsy-daisy.
噢,起来
Oh, please. Wait. Wait.
求你,慢点
Oh, you're such a crybaby.
你还真是个爱哭宝宝
There you go.
行了,舒服吧?
Comfy?
好极了
Perfect.
你真孩子气
Such a kidder.
I have a big surprise for you.
我要给你一个大大的惊喜 但你得先做点事情
But first there's something you must do.
You don't suppose I could have a little snack
在我等待惊喜时 你不会介意给我一些点心吧?
while I'm waiting for the surprise?
I'll get you everything you want, but you must listen first.
你要什么我都会给你 但你先要听我说
Sometimes my thinking is a little muddy.
有时我的想法胡涂,我接受
I accept that.
It's why I couldn't remember all the things they were asking me
曾经为此在丹佛的证人席上 他们问我,我却什么也想不起来
on the witness stand in Denver.
But this time, I thought clearly.
但是这次,我想的很清楚 我问上帝关于你的事
I asked God about you,
and God said, "I delivered him unto you
上帝说,「我把他交给你 这样你就能为他领路了」
"so that you may show him the way."
Show me the way?
- 给我领路?    - 是的
Yes.
无  题  保罗?谢尔登著
When I mentioned a snack,
顺路的话,我想要的是…点心
I was thinking more along the lines
of a cheese-and-crackers kind of thing.
干酪、饼干之类的东西
Paul, this is no time for jokes.
保罗,这不是开玩笑的时候
You must rid the world of this filth.
你得从世界上 清除掉这些精神污染
You want me to burn my book?
你要我烧我的书?
I know this may be difficult for you, but it's for the best.
我知道这对于你很难 但这样作是最好的
It's really not difficult at all.
这真的一点也不难
My agent made dozens of copies.
我的经纪人有许多副本 在纽约会有拍卖会
There's gonna be an auction in New York.
Every publishing house in New York is reading it now.
出版社正在审阅此书
So if you want me to burn my book, fine.
若你要我烧自己的书,好吧
You're not really ridding the world of anything.
但你并没有除掉些什么
Then light the match, Paul.
那么点火柴吧
It's no big deal.
没什么大不了
So you've indicated.
你已经表明了,动手吧
Do it.
I know this is the only copy, Paul.
这是唯一的一份,保罗
When you were 24, you wrote your first book
这是你的第一本书,没留副本 你没想到会有人重视它
and you didn't make a copy
because you didn't think anybody would take it seriously.
But they did. And ever since, you've never made any copies
但是他们很重视 从此你就不留副本,因为你迷信
because you're superstitious.
也因此,你总是回到银溪旅馆
It's why you always come back to the Silver Creek Lodge.
You told that story to Merv Griffin 11 years ago.
你曾对梅尔夫?格利芬说过
Merv Griffin.
格利芬
I'll tell you what, it doesn't ever have to be published.
我告诉你吧,此书不会出版
No one ever has to read it.
没人会读到它,我仅为自己留着
I'll just keep it for myself.
No one will even know it exists.
甚至没人会知道它的存在
As long as it does exist, your mind won't ever be free.
只要它还存在 你的思想就不会有自由
I think you should light the match, Paul.
我想你该点火啦,保罗
Can't you see it's what God wants?
你就看不出这是上帝的旨意吗? 你这样绝顶聪明
You're so brilliant,
我相信毫无疑问你会明白的
I would think you'd certainly be able to see that.
We're put on this Earth to help people, Paul.
我们来到世上 是要帮助别人,保罗
Like I'm trying to help you.
正像我,在设法帮助你一样
Please, help me help you.
拜托,让我来帮帮你吧
You're doing the right thing.
你这就做对了
Oh, my goodness!
我的天哪!上帝!哦,我的…
Goodness gracious! Oh, my!
Oh, my goodness! Heavens to Betsy!
天啊!上帝呀!
Oh, my goodness! Oh, my goodness!
噢,我的天呀!噢,我的天呀!
Heavens to Betsy! Oh, goodness!
上帝呀!噢,天哪!
Well, isn't that an oogy mess?
喔,这下烧光了
[HELICOPTER WHIRRING]
That's the Steadman place down there.
那边是斯特德曼家
And that's the Wilkes farm straight ahead.
前面是威尔斯农场
That's no '65 Mustang.
没看到65年的野马车
Well, there's nothing else out this way.
这里没什么了,我们回去吧
Let's circle back.
I do believe the winters are getting shorter and shorter every year.
我相信冬天会一年比一年短
People say it has something to do with the ozone layer.
人们说是这和臭氧层有关
What do you think?
你认为呢?
I don't know.
我不知道
Yeah, well, it's a theory.
是呀,这是一种理论
Here's your Novril.
你的止痛药
Hi, we're back.
再回来现场,提醒一下 我们的观众选了谁
Now, you're gonna have to remind us who the audience chose.
- 他们选了凯文 - 他们选了凯文
They chose Kevin. They chose Kevin.
[AUDIENCE APPLAUDING] Congratulations! Say hello to Kevin Andrews.
我们跟凯文打个招呼
Hi, Kevin. Hi, how you doing, Chuck?
- 嗨,凯文 - 嗨,你好,查克?
Fine, make yourself at home back there
就当你在家好了 谢瑞会告诉我们约会的事
and Sheri will tell us about the date.
Okay. First of all, I picked out a very classy restaurant.
首先,我挑一间气派的餐厅
It was so classy, and he shows up without no tie...
餐厅很优雅,他却没系领带
See, isn't this nice?
看看这不错吧?
Great, I always wanted to visit the other side of the room.
不错,我一直想看房间另一边
Look what I got for you.
看我给你买了什么
An electric razor, so you can shave yourself now.
电动刮胡刀 你可以自己刮胡子了
[WHIRRING]
If I knew this was gonna be the surprise, I'd have burned all my books.
如果早知有此惊喜 我宁愿烧掉所有的书
Now, don't poke fun.
不,别说笑话了
This is a very big day for you, Paul.
今天是你的大日子,保罗 你只要坐着我会安排一切的
You just sit tight and I'll set everything up.
Set what up?
- 安排什么? - 那是个大惊喜
That's the big surprise.
Your new studio.
你的新书房
After all, writers do need a place to work.
毕竟,作家需要有个地方工作
Work? You mean, write?
工作?你是指写作?
What in the world do you think I'd write?
你认为我还会写什么呢?
Oh, but, Paul, I don't think.
保罗,我不认为我知道
I know.
你已经烧掉了那肮脏的手稿 你可以重新开始做擅长的事情
Now that you've gotten rid of that nasty manuscript,
you can go back to doing what you're great at.
You're gonna write a new novel,
你要写作一本新的小说 会是你最杰出的成就
your greatest achievement ever.
Misery's Return.
米瑟丽复活
"Misery's Return"?
米瑟丽复活?
I know you didn't mean it when you killed her,
我知道你当时杀掉她并非有意 现在你要改邪归正
and now you'll make it right.
It'll be a book in my honor
这将是一本给我荣誉的书
for saving your life and nursing you back to health.
因为救了你,和护理你恢复健康
Oh, Paul, you're gonna make me the envy of the whole world.
保罗,你会使我 成为全世界羡慕的对象
You just expect me to whip something off, is that it?
你要我随便写写,是吗?
I expect nothing less than your masterpiece.
别的我都指望不到 你有杰作
You do understand
你确实不太明白 那些书通常是怎么写出来的
that this is not the ordinary way in which books get written.
I mean, some people might actually
我想人们会 认为这种情形很奇怪
consider this an oddball situation.
I have total confidence in your brilliance.
但我对你的才华有信心
Besides, the view will inspire you.
而且,风景也会激发你
You just inhale that. I'll be right back.
你欣赏吧,我很快回来
I guess you don't get bothered by neighbors much.
- 你不觉得会打扰邻居吧 - 这你不用担心
Don't you worry about that.
你完全被隔离 这样你就可以专心写作
You'll have total solitude so you can concentrate on your work.
Great.
好极了
I got you this expensive paper to type on,
我给你买了昂贵的打字纸
and I got a great deal on this 50-pound clunker
这打字机划算,只花了50磅 因为少了N字母的键
on account of it's missing an "N."
I told the sales lady, "N" was one of the letters
我对女店员说我最喜爱的作家 名字中有N字母
in my favorite writer's name.
It's-- It's two of the letters in my favorite nurse's name, Annie.
我喜欢的护士的名字 安妮有两个N字母
You fooler.
你这傻瓜,我做得还好吧?
Did I do good?
You did great.
你做得很好
There is just one little thing.
只有一件小事情
I can't work on this paper.
我不能用这些纸,看吧 很容易洇污
See, it's Corrasable Bond and it smudges.
So I thought maybe if you went back into town,
我想,也许 你如果可以回镇上去
you could bring me some white long-grained mimeo.
你会买一些白色的长纤维纸
But mine cost the most, so I don't see how it can smudge.
但这是最贵的,我不明白 怎么会有洇污呢
Come here, I'll show you.
过来,我给你看
[WINDING]
[TYPING]
Oh.
的确是有洇污 不是那么让人喜欢
It does smudge after all.
Isn't that fascinating?
I thought you'd be interested.
我认为你会有兴趣
I'd-- I'd like for you to be in on everything, Annie.
我想要你参与一切,安妮
Not just the finished book, but how it's written.
不只是完成的书 而是如何写作一本书
Thank you for thinking of me.
谢谢你想到我
Anything else I can get while I'm in town?
我到镇上去 还有什么想要买呢?
Any other crucial requirements that need satisfying?
还有什么关键的要求 需要满足?
Would you like a tiny tape recorder?
你要一个微型录音机吗?
Or how about a handmade set of writing slippers?
或者一双手工写作拖鞋怎么样?
Just the paper will be fine.
不用,只买纸就可以了
Are you sure?
你肯定吗?如果你要的话 我可以把整个商店都搬回来
'Cause if you want, I'll bring back the whole store for you.
Annie, what's the matter?
安妮,怎么了?
"What's the matter?" I'll tell you what's the matter!
怎么了?我告诉你怎么了!
I go out of my way for you!
我为你做所有的一切 我想方设法,让你高兴
I do everything to try and make you happy!
I feed you! I clean you! I dress you!
我给你吃饭,洗澡,穿衣! 我得到了什么感谢?
And what thanks do I get?
"Oh, you bought the wrong paper, Annie.
「你买错纸了,安妮」 「我不能用这种纸写作,安妮」
"I can't write on this paper, Annie."
Well, I'll get your stupid paper,
我会给你买那扯蛋的纸 但是你最好向我…
but you just better start showing me
a little more appreciation around here, Mr. Man!
向我多少表示一点感激! 了不起先生!
[GROANING]
Shit.
该死
Come on, you've written about this, now do it.
来吧,你曾写过这个的 现在用上了
[CLICKING]
What do you know? It actually works.
你没想到吧?还真管用
What a surprise.
真没想到
You crazy bitch.
你这个疯母狗
[GROANS]
[GRUNTS]
[GRUNTING]
[CLICKING]
Paul, I've got your paper!
保罗,我买好了纸
I hope it's enough.
希望足够吧,是三盒长纤维纸
Three reams of long-grained mimeo.
Just the kind you asked for.
是你要的那一种
Paul.
保罗,你满头是汗
You're dripping with perspiration.
Your color is very hectic.
你看起来慌慌张张的 你刚才做什么了?
What have you been doing?
You know damn well what I've been doing.
该死的,你知道我一直做什么 我一直坐在这里受苦
I've been sitting here suffering.
I need my pills.
我要我的药
Poor dear.
好可怜,让我把你扶上床 我再给你拿
Let's get you back in bed, and I'll get them for you.
I want my pills now!
我现在就要!
It'll only take a second.
- 只少等一会     - 不!
No!
I want my pain to go away, Annie.
我要止痛,安妮,马上
Please, make it go away.
求你,给我止痛
Please, Annie.
求你
Please.
It just breaks my heart to see you like this.
看你这样,让我好伤心
I've done a lot of thinking on the drive.
我在开车时 一直想来想去,给你
Here you go.
And I'm absolutely certain.
我绝对相信,我 总是不受欢迎的主要原因
The main reason I've never been
more popular is because of my temper.
是因为我的脾气
You must be so mad at me.
你一定很生我的气 说实话,现在就说
The truth, now.
Well, who doesn't let off a little steam every once in a while?
这个…
有谁不会隔三差五地 发泄一下呢?
My genius needs his rest before he writes.
写作之前 我的天才要休息一会儿
Footsies up.
抬起双脚
There you go.
行了
Okay.
Here.
给你这个
In case you think of any ideas.
免得你有什么想法时会忘了
Well, I wouldn't expect too much.
好吧,我不会怎么样的
Don't be silly. You'll be brilliant.
别傻了,你会很出色的
Think of me as your inspiration.
把我当成你的灵感
I have faith in you, my darling.
我对你很有信心,我亲爱的
Catch this.
接住
"My darling."
「我亲爱的」
The presumption must now be that Paul Sheldon is dead.
根据推测,保罗?谢尔登 极有可能已经死亡
We know that he somehow managed to crawl outside his vehicle,
我们知道他设法爬出车外
but we have been unable to find his body
但没能在意外现场,及附近 找到他的尸体
anywhere in the vicinity of the accident.
We also know that if anyone had found him,
我们也知道,若有人发现了他 他们会送他去医院
they would've taken him to an area hospital.
Undoubtedly, he is buried somewhere out there in the snow.
无疑他是被掩埋在 此地某处雪下
We'll find him after the first thaw.
雪融后我们会立刻找到他
That is, unless the animals didn't get to him first,
当然,除非有猛兽对他先行下手 但这也是极有可能的
which is a distinct possibility.
That was a statement from Colorado Police Chief, Sherman Douglas.
刚才是科罗拉多州警局 局长谢尔曼?道格拉斯的谈话
We will be updating you...
我们将会为您报导最新…
You don't think he's dead, do you?
你不认为他死了,你说是吗?
Well, he might well be, but not the way they say.
嗯,他也许吧 但不是他们说的那样
He never crawled out of that car by himself.
他并没有自己爬出车外
You can see the dents on the door there.
你可以看见车门有凹痕 有人把他弄了出来
Someone pulled him out.
操操操操操操操
I'm sorry, Paul. This is all wrong.
抱歉保罗,这根本不对
What? You'll have to do it over again.
- 什么?     - 你必须重写
It's not worthy of you. Throw it all out.
这对你没有价值,扔掉吧
Except for that part of naming the gravedigger after me.
除了跟我同姓氏的挖墓者 那一部分,你可以保留
You can leave that in.
I really value your criticism,
我很看重你的批评 但是也许我们都匆忙一点了
but maybe we're being a little bit hasty here.
Paul, what you've written just isn't fair.
保罗,你写的不合情理
Not fair?
- 不合情理?     - 对
That's right.
我小时候在加州故乡
When I was growing up in Bakersfield,
my favorite thing in all the world
我最喜欢的事情 是周六下午去电影院看连续剧
was to go to the movies on Saturday afternoons for the chapter plays.
Cliffhangers.
- 〈绝岭雄风〉 - 那我知道,了不起先生
I know that, Mr. Man!
They also call them serials. I'm not stupid, you know!
他们也叫系列剧,我不傻 你该知道
Anyway, my favorite was  Rocket Man.
我最爱看的还是〈火箭人〉 有一次放映没有刹车的那一集
And once it was a no-brakes chapter,
and the bad guys stuck him in a car on a mountain road,
坏人把他困在山路上的车里
and knocked him out and welded the doors shut,
打晕了他,把门关上,焊死 破坏了刹车要弄死他
and tore out the brakes and started him to his death.
And he woke up and tried to steer and tried to get out.
他醒来后 想控制方向,再逃出去
But the car went off a cliff before he could escape
但在他逃出之前 车子跌下悬崖,起火燃烧
and it crashed and burned, and I was so upset and excited!
对此我是如此紧张而兴奋!
And the next week, you better believe, I was first in line.
下个星期我又第一个去看 刚开始还是重放上周的结尾
And they always start with the end of the last week.
And there was Rocket Man, trying to get out,
还是火箭人想逃脱那一段 车子冲向悬崖
and here comes the cliff.
就在汽车跌下悬崖时,他逃了出来 孩子们马上齐声欢呼
And just before the car went off the cliff, he jumped free!
And all the kids cheered!
But I didn't cheer.
但我没有 我立刻站起来大叫
I stood right up and started shouting,
"This isn't what happened last week!
「上次不是这样,你们都忘了吗? 」
"Have you all got amnesia?
"They just cheated us! This isn't fair!
「他们欺骗我们,这不公平!」
"He didn't get out of the cock-a-doodie car!"
「他没有从那狗日的车里逃出来!」
They always cheated like that in...
他们在连续剧里经常这样做
Chapter plays.
但你不行 我的米瑟丽不能这样
But not you.
Not with my Misery.
Remember Ian did ride for Dr. Cleary at the end of the last book,
记得伊恩骑马去找克利医生吗 在书的结尾,马跨越栅栏跌倒了
but his horse fell jumping that fence.
And Ian broke his shoulder and his ribs
伊恩摔断了肩膀和肋骨 整夜躺在沟里,没有找到医生
and lay all night in the ditch,
and he never reached the doctor.
因此不可能试着输血,救她一命
So there couldn't have been any experimental blood transfusion
that saved her life.
Misery was buried in the ground at the end, Paul,
到最后米瑟丽被埋在地下,保罗
so you'll have to start there.
所以你必须从那儿开始
Is it fair?
这合情理吗? 我该接着这样写吗?
Should I continue?
You better.
你这样最好啦!
Oh, Paul!
噢保罗!当伊恩意识到
When Ian realized that the reason they'd buried Misery alive
他们之所以活埋了米瑟丽 是因为蜂螫她已经昏迷
was because the bee sting had put her in that temporary coma.
And when gravedigger Wilkes remembered how 30 years earlier
当挖墓工人威尔斯 回想起30年前
the same thing had happened to Lady Evelyn-Hyde!
同样的事情发生在 伊夫琳夫人身上
And then old Dr. Cleary deduced
老克利医生推断,米瑟丽 一定是夫人失散多年的女儿
that Misery must be Lady Evelyn-Hyde's long-lost daughter
because of the rarity of deadly bee stings.
这罕见的致命蜂螫 让我的心狂跳起来了
My heart just leapt!
I've known from the very first book
从第一本书,我就知道米瑟丽 必定出身贵族,我没有错
that Misery had to be born of nobility,
and I was right!
是的
Yeah.
保罗,你写完后我可以接着看吗? 我可以补上N字母
Oh, Paul, can I read each chapter when you finish?
I can fill in the "N's."
Will she be her old self, now that Ian has dug her out,
伊恩把她挖出来,她是跟从前一样 还是她会失去记忆?
or will she have amnesia?
Have to wait.
那得等待
Will she still love him with that special, perfect love?
她仍会以特别的完美的爱 去爱他吗?
You'll have to wait.
你得等着
Not even a hint?
甚至没有一点点提示?
Mmm-mmm.
[EXCLAIMING]
米瑟丽活着,米瑟丽活着! 这是多么浪漫!
Misery's alive! Misery's alive!
Oh, it's so romantic!
这让屋子里都充满了浪漫!
Oh, this whole house is gonna be filled with romance!
I'm gonna put on my Liberace records!
我会放利伯拉斯的唱片
You do like Liberace, don't you?
你很喜欢利伯拉斯,不是吗?
Whenever he played Radio City,
当他演唱〈城市电波〉时 你认为谁会坐在第一排?
who do you think was right there in the front row?
I'm gonna play my records all day long to inspire you.
我要整天放唱片,激发你的灵感
He's my all-time favorite.
他一直都是我的最爱
Annie?
安妮
Would you have dinner with me tonight?
你今天晚上会和我共进晚餐吗?
To celebrate Misery's return.
庆祝米瑟丽复活
I couldn't have done it without you.
没有你我就写不好
Oh, Paul.
噢,保罗
It would be an honor.
那是荣幸
No, he's not here.
不,他不在
I don't know where he is.
我不知道他去哪了 他从来都不告诉我什么
He never tells me anything anymore.
He's probably out having an affair somewhere.
他可能在外面有外遇吧
Wait a minute. He's coming in now.
等一下,他回来了
It's Jim Taylor.
是吉姆?泰勒 想知道你跟谁有外遇
He wants to know who you're having an affair with.
Hello, Jim. What's doing?
吉姆你好,有什么事吗?
Jim, we've been through this before.
吉姆,我们以前已经说过了
If you're gonna have benches out in front of your store,
如果你的店前面有长椅 人们就会坐在上面
people are gonna wanna sit on them.
Well, I don't like him either,
好吧,我也不喜欢他 但我不会过去让他离开
but I'm not gonna come over there and tell him to move.
Give my best to Denise. Bye.
替我问候丹尼丝,再见
Well, whoever she is, she sure likes to read a lot.
那么不管她是谁,她挺爱看书
Virginia, I'm flattered that you think I've got that much energy.
维吉尼娅
你夸奖我精力充沛 让我受宠若惊
I figured that if I can't find Paul Sheldon,
我想如果找不到保罗?谢尔登 至少可以查出他写了些什么
at least I can find out what he wrote about.
What do you expect to find?
你指望查出什么?
A story about a guy who drove his car off a cliff in a snowstorm?
关于一个人开车在暴风雪中 冲下山崖的故事
You see, it's just that kind of sarcasm
你看,就是这种冷嘲热讽 让我们的婚姻充满激情
that's given our marriage real spice.
[I'LL BE SEEING YOU PLAYING ON RECORD PLAYER]
? 我会见到你 ?
? I'll be seeing you
? In all the old familiar places ?
? 在所有熟悉的老地方 ?
I hope you like it.
- 希望你喜欢     - 诱人极了
It looks wonderful.
So do you.
你也一样
[GIGGLING]
I've never had meat loaf this good.
我从没吃过这么好吃的肉饼 你怎么做的?
What do you do to it?
My secret is I only use fresh tomatoes, never canned.
秘诀是用新鲜西红柿,不用罐头的
And to give it that little extra zip,
还要添加一些 罐头火腿和碎牛肉
I mix in some Spam with the ground beef.
Can't get this in a restaurant in New York.
在纽约的餐厅是吃不到的
Let's have a toast.
- 让我们敬酒     - 敬酒?
A toast?
对,为米瑟丽干杯
Yes. To, um, to Misery.
Let me pour you some wine.
我来给你斟酒
[EXCLAIMS]
不
No.
To Misery.
为米瑟丽干杯
Wait.
等一下,让我们好好享用 你有蜡烛吗?
Let's do this right. Do you have any candles?
Oh, um, I don't know. I...
我不清楚,可能吧
I think so. I'll go look.
我去找找看
Did you study decorating or do you just have a flair?
你是学过装潢还是有天分呢?
Oh, you!
你啊真是的
I just picked things up over the years.
这些年来是我在打理
Well, it certainly says you.
很有你的风格
You really think so?
你真的这么认为吗?
Absolutely.
当然啦
Listen, if you can't find any, it's okay.
你找不到就算了 我只不过觉得那样会更好
I just thought it'd be nice.
Are you kidding?
你在开玩笑吧? 如果有人说,我会…
If anyone had ever told me that one day
I'd be having a candle-lit dinner
在自己家里跟保罗?谢尔登 共进烛光晚餐
with Paul Sheldon in my own house,
I would've checked both legs to see which one was being pulled.
那我一定会认为他是在 拿我开玩笑
Will this do?
这样可以吧?
It's perfect.
太完美了
To Misery and to Annie Wilkes, who brought her back to life.
为米瑟丽和安妮?威尔斯干杯 是她让米瑟丽复活
Oh, Paul, I get goosebumps every time I think about it.
保罗,每次我想起来 都会起鸡皮疙瘩
[EXCLAIMING]
Oh, my God. What have I done?
我的天啊,我做了什么?
Oh, I'm so sorry, Paul.
我很抱歉,保罗
I ruined your beautiful toast.
我搞砸了你美好的敬酒
Will you ever forgive me?
你能原谅我吗?
Here, let me pour another one.
来,我再倒一杯
Can we pretend this never happened?
我们可以当作没发生过吗?
To Misery.
为米瑟丽干杯
为米瑟丽
[TYPING]
第5章
第12章
Paul, this is positively the best Misery you've ever written.
保罗,这肯定是你 写过的最好的米瑟丽
第19章
第28章
第35章
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
Here's your pills.
这是你的药
Annie?
安妮?
Annie, what is it?
安妮,怎么了?
The rain.
下雨
Sometimes it gives me the blues.
有时这让我心情压抑
When you first came here,
你刚来这里时,我只爱 保罗?谢尔登,作为作家那部分
I only loved the writer part of Paul Sheldon.
But now, I know I love the rest of him, too.
但我现在知道,我也爱 他的其余部分
I know you don't love me.
我知道,你不爱我
Don't say you do.
别说你爱我
You're a beautiful, brilliant, famous man of the world,
你是世上的英俊… 才华出众而且著名的男人
and I'm not a movie star type.
可我,并不是,电影明星一类
You'll never know the fear of losing someone like you
你永远也不会知道,我这因爱 而害怕失去你的心情
if you're someone like me.
- 即使你像我一样 - 你怎么会失去我?
Why would you lose me?
The book's almost finished.
书马上就完成了
Your legs are getting better.
你的腿也好起来了
Soon you'll be wanting to leave.
很快你就会想离开
Why would I leave?
我为何要离开? 我喜欢这里
I like it here.
That's very kind of you.
你这样说真好 但我打赌这根本就不是真的
But I'll bet it's not altogether true.
I have this gun.
我这把枪
Sometimes I think about using it.
有时候我想用它
I better go now.
我最好现在就去吧
I might put bullets in it.
说不定我会给它装子弹
[DOOR CLOSING]
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
[CAR ENGINE STARTING]
"There is a justice higher than that of man.
「有比人类更高的公义」
"I will be judged by him."
「我会由它来判决」
What?
什么?
They're hauling Misery into court.
他们把米瑟丽推上法庭
That's nice.
那好
"There is a justice higher than that of man.
「有比人类更高的公义」
"I will be judged by him."
「我会由它来判决」
(上)保罗?谢尔登现在何处?  (下)保罗?谢尔登推定死亡
〈往事历历〉
本地投资银行家  卡尔?威尔斯 跳楼自杀  (手写)怀念亲爱的爸爸 于父亲节
优秀的护校学生摔死
护校荣誉生 安妮?威尔斯
安妮?威尔斯 出任重症监护室护士
(左)退休小儿科医生 在本地医院昏迷而后死亡
(右)威尔斯获提名 为本县产科护士长
婴儿露西 在医院挣扎五周后 死亡 父母悲痛欲绝
埃尔德里奇县纪念医院 第二宗新生婴儿死亡案  (手写)另外一名婴儿
医院婴儿死 护士受盘问
医院育婴室 再次发生 婴幼儿死亡
产科护士身陷囹圄 又有婴儿死亡「魔鬼女」被捕
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
[CAR APPROACHING]
[DOOR OPENING]
[DOOR CLOSING]
MAN ON TV: Welcome to Love Connection!
欢迎来到〈情牵一线〉
Where old-fashioned romance meets modern-day technology.
以往的浪漫结合现代技术…
Where you hear all the intimate details of the date.
你可以听到约会对象 一切亲昵细节
See you in the morning.
早上见
[THUNDER CLAPPING]
[GRUNTS]
[DOOR CLOSING]
MAN ON TV: I'm supposed to be in the finale of my show right now,
本来应该进入节目的尾声了
but I'm having such a wonderful time...
但我度过了如此 美好的时光,让我…
Paul.
保罗
Hmm?
嗯?
I know you've been out.
我知道你曾经外出
What?
- 什么? - 你曾经离开你的房间
You've been out of your room.
No, I haven't.
不,我没有
Paul.
保罗
My little ceramic penguin in the study always faces due south.
我书房里的瓷器小企鹅 始终是面向南方的
I don't... I don't know what you're talking about.
我不,我不知道你在说什么
Ceramic penguin?
瓷器企鹅?
Is this what you're looking for?
你在找这个吗?
I know you've been out twice, Paul.
我知道你有两次外出,保罗
At first, I couldn't figure out how you did it,
起初我弄不明白你怎么办到的
but last night I found your key.
但是昨晚我发现了你的钥匙
I know I left my scrapbook out.
我知道我的剪贴簿放在外面 我能猜到你会怎么想我
I can imagine what you might be thinking of me.
But you see, Paul, it's all okay.
不过你看,保罗,这没啥了不起
Last night, it came so clear.
昨晚,我把一切都想清楚了
I realized you just need more time.
我知道,你是需要多一些些时间
Eventually, you'll come to accept the idea of being here.
最后你会 自觉自愿地留在这里
Paul, do you know about the early days
保罗,你可知道南非早期的 金伯利钻石矿吗?
at the Kimberley diamond mines?
Do you know what they did to the native workers who stole diamonds?
你知道他们怎么对付 偷钻石的工人?
Don't worry, they didn't kill them.
放心,没有杀死他们
That would be like junking a Mercedes
那就像仅仅一个弹簧损坏 便要丢弃一辆奔驰轿车太傻了
just because it had a broken spring.
No, if they caught them,
不,如果抓住了 他们要确保工人还能继续工作
they had to make sure they could go on working,
but they also had to make sure they could never run away.
但是也必须确保 那些工人永远无法逃跑
The operation was called "hobbling."
这种做法称为「跛行」
Annie,
安妮,无论你想做什么 求求你不要这样
whatever you're thinking about doing, please don't do it.
Anne, for God...
- 安妮,看在上帝的份上… - 亲爱的,相信我
[SHUSHING] Darling. Trust me.
God's sake! It's for the best.
- 上帝呀! - 这是最好的啦
Annie, please!
安妮,求求你!
Almost done. Just one more.
就完了,还有一只脚
God, I love you.
上帝呀,我爱你
[TIRES SCREECHING]
[CAR HORN HONKING]
You cock-a-doodie!
你这狗日的!
Sit on this!
- 去你的吧!     - 你这混蛋!
You poop!
Just leave it, all right?
离它远点,好吗
Oh, I like that tone.
我喜欢这语气
How many times do I have to tell you?
要我说多少次? 我放的都有一定地方的
I have a system here.
Where the hell is that thing?
- 那该死的东西在哪? - 什么东西?
What thing?
那东西!
The thing!
Here it is. Right where it's supposed to be.
- 找到了,它在这儿应该在这儿 - 这是什么?
What is it?
I'm not sure. Maybe nothing.
- 我不太清楚,也许没什么 - 嗯,我很庆幸你找到了
Well, I'm glad you found it.
There's that spice again.
又在刺激了
医院育婴室 再次发生 婴幼儿死亡
产科护士身陷囹圄 又有婴儿死亡「魔鬼女」被捕
「魔鬼女」声称无辜
威尔斯在法院外对记者说
「有比人类更高的公义 我会由它来判决」
ANNIE: Come on, Mizzy. Come on!
过来,小米瑟丽,快点呀
Hi, pumpkin!
嗨,小可爱!
Such a kidder.
真是孩子气! 过来吧,米瑟丽
Come on, Misery!
Come on, Mizzy.
[BELL RINGING]
Hey, Pete.
- 嗨,皮特     - 头儿
Buster.
- 回答我几件事 - 如果我能的话
Answer me a couple of things.
If I can.
Do you have any new Paul Sheldon books?
你有保罗?谢尔登的新书吗?
Well, we had a batch.
当然,有过一大堆 三天内就卖光了
Sold them all out in three days.
You wouldn't happen to know
你或许知道 威尔斯小姐买过,记得吗?
if Miss Wilkes bought one of them, would you?
Are you kidding?
你开玩笑?那伙计每次有新书 她便要我给她保留头一本
Every time that fellow writes a new book,
she has me set aside the first copy.
Has she been, uh, buying anything odd lately?
她最近买过什么奇怪的东西吗?
Miss Wilkes?
威尔斯小姐?还不是老样子
Same old stuff.
Lest you call paper odd.
- 除非买纸也算奇怪 - 报纸吗?
Newspaper?
不,是打字用的那种
No. The typing kind.
Oh, that kind. Nothing odd about that.
就那种,也没什么奇怪的
Miss Wilkes done something?
- 威尔斯小姐出事了吗? - 没事儿了
Not a thing.
[CAR APPROACHING]
[SCREAMS]
I don't think I'll ever understand you.
我从来不明白你,我给你弄吃的 整天24小时伺候你
I cook your meals, I tend to you practically 24 hours a day
and you continue to fight me.
而你却不停地反抗我
When are we going to develop a sense of trust?
我们俩什么时候才能 互相信任呢?
Oh, my.
噢,我的…
I'm sorry, I didn't mean to startle you,
抱歉,我不是有意吓吓你 但你没给我机会敲门
but you didn't give me a chance to knock.
I guess you can tell from my reaction,
我猜你从我的反应,就看得出 我一向不习惯外人来这里
I'm not all that used to visitors out here.
What can I do for you?
我能为你做什么?
Well, I was wondering,
我不太肯定,也许你会 碰巧知道保罗?谢尔登的事?
do you happen to know anything about Paul Sheldon?
What do you wanna know?
你想知道什么?
Well, anything you could tell me might help.
噢,随你告诉我,都会有帮助
Well, he was born in Worcester, Massachusetts 45 years ago,
嗯,45年前,他在马萨诸塞州 伍斯特市出生
the only child of Franklin and Helene Sheldon,
富兰克林和海伦?谢尔登的独子 是个平庸学生,主修历史
mediocre student, majored in history.
Well, that... That isn't exactly
这个…这些并不完全是 我想要知道的
the kind of information I'm after.
你知道,他已失踪好长时间了…
You see, he's been missing for quite some time now...
I know. It's so upsetting.
我知道,这着实令人不安 我是他的头号书迷
I'm his number one fan.
我已经收集了他的所有的书 甚至于他的每一句话
I've got all his books, every sentence he ever put down.
I'm so proud of my Paul Sheldon collection.
我为我收藏了 保罗?谢尔登而骄傲
Well, here I am, prattling on and my manners have just flown away.
哦,我这样说的没完没了 而我的礼貌却飞得不见踪影
I haven't invited you in. Please.
我还没邀请你进来,请吧
Thank you.
谢谢你
Of course, you must know all about that horrible accident.
你应该都知道那个 可怕的事故了
Mind if I take a look around?
- 介意我四处看看吗? - 当然不会
Of course not.
That accident almost killed me, too.
那个意外,也几乎要了我的命
I prayed when I heard the news.
得知消息后我便祈祷
I got down on my knees and I begged for it not to be true.
我跪倒在地下,我祈求那不是真的
You're gonna laugh at what I'm about to say,
你会笑话我所说的 那你就笑话吧,我才不在乎
but go ahead, I don't care.
When I was praying, God told me to get ready.
我祈祷时 上帝告诉我要做好准备
Get ready for what?
- 做好什么准备? - 作他的替身
To be his replacement.
He gave so much pleasure to so many people.
他给那么多人 带来那么多欢乐
There's a shortage of pleasure on the planet these days,
或许你没注意,如今这世间 欢乐已经越来越少了
in case you hadn't noticed.
God told me, since I was his number one fan,
上帝告诉我 因为我是他的头号书迷
that I should make up new stories as if I was Paul Sheldon.
我就该编写新的故事,好像 我就是保罗?谢尔登
So I went to town and I bought a typewriter
因此我去镇上买了打字机 还有打字纸
and paper to type on,
跟保罗?谢尔登用的是同一种
the same kind Paul Sheldon used.
And I turned the guest bedroom into a writing studio.
我把客房也变成了写作书房
Would you like to see it? Sure.
- 你想看看吗?     - 当然
It's right this way.
它在这边
I know how he wrote, the kinds of words he used,
我知道他怎样写,他用哪些字
the wonderful stories he told.
他写出了那些精彩的故事
I've spent the last four weeks
我用了四周时间,试图 模仿保罗?谢尔登的写作
trying to write like Paul Sheldon,
but I can't do it right.
但我写的并不很像
I try and I try and I know all the words, but it's just not the same.
我试一次,再试一次,我知道 所有字句,但就是不一样
Well, maybe it takes a while to get the hang of it.
喔,也许要花一段时间 才能掌握
I could give you a couple of hundred pages of mine,
我可以给你看写好的几百页 你告诉我你的看法
and you could tell me what you think.
我并非那种评论家
I'm not much of a critic.
Well, I just thought...
哦,我刚才想…
Oh, look at me, you'd think I'd never had a guest before.
哦,看我,你会以为 我从来没接待过客人!
Would you like a nice hot cup of cocoa?
- 你要一杯热可可吗? - 不,真的,我不…
No, really, I...
这不麻烦,有现成的
It's no trouble.
There's some already made.
Must get lonely, living out here all by yourself.
你一个人独自在这里生活 想必很孤单吧
Well, I always say if you can't enjoy your own company,
嗯,我是想你如果不能乐于独处 又如何同别人相处呢
you're not fit company for anyone else.
Well, you've got a point there.
嗯,你说的有道理
Here you are.
- 给你的 - 好吧,谢谢威尔斯小姐
Thanks, Miss Wilkes
但是我不想占用你更多时间了
but I don't wanna take up anymore of your time.
I best be going.
我最好还是走了
But you didn't even taste your cocoa.
不过你还没喝一口可可
Well, I'm sure it's wonderful,
我相信味道肯定很好 但我真的该回去了
but I really should be getting back.
Well, if you wouldn't mind,
你不介意的话,也许 我会另找时间再来拜访
perhaps I could pay you another visit sometime.
I'd be delighted. Now that you know the way.
我会很高兴,现在你认识路了
[CLATTERING]
Miss Wilkes?
威尔斯小姐?
Miss Wilkes, are you all right?
威尔斯小姐,你没事吧?
PAUL: Here!
在这里!
Here! I'm down here!
在这里!我在下面!
I'm down here!
我在下面!
Mr. Sheldon?
谢尔登先生吗?
[GUN FIRES]
Don't feel bad, Paul.
别难过,保罗
It was bound to happen sooner or later.
这事或迟或早都必定要发生
It's a sign.
这是一个信号
You see, I've known for some time why I was chosen to save you.
你看,我早就知道了 我为什么被选中,来救你一命
You and I were meant to be together forever.
你和我,是早已注定了 要永远在一起的
But now our time in this world must end.
而现在,我们在这世上的日子 应该结束了
But don't worry, Paul.
但是不用担心,保罗 我已作好了必要的准备
I've prepared for what must be done.
I put two bullets in my gun.
我的枪里装了两颗子弹 一颗为你,一颗为我
One for you and one for me.
Oh, darling, it'll be so beautiful.
亲爱的,这将会非常美妙的
木炭引燃剂
Now, don't be afraid.
现在不用害怕
I love you.
我爱你
I love you, too.
我也爱你,更爱
And you're right.
而且你说的很对 我们注定,要永远在一起
We are meant to be together.
And I know we must die.
我也知道,我们一定会死
But it must be so that Misery can live.
但是,也必须是这样… 让米瑟丽活着
We have the power to give Misery eternal life.
我们有能力 给米瑟丽,永恒的生命
We must finish the book.
我们必须完成这本书
But the time is now.
现在是时候了 很快其它人会来
Soon others will come.
It's almost finished.
就快要完成了
By dawn,
到了黎明时分
we'll be able to give Misery back to the world.
我们就能让米瑟丽 重返人间
I'll fix you something to eat.
我给你弄吃的东西
连续三天三夜,米瑟丽在哭,…
Oh, Paul, I'm dying.
保罗,我快要死了
Does she wind up with Ian or Winthorne?
她是和伊恩 还是和温德索恩在一起?
You'll know very soon.
你很快就会知道
I've just thought of the last chapter.
我刚刚开始最后一章
You know, when I finish,
你知道,我写完之后 我希望一切都是完美的
I'd like everything to be perfect.
I'll need three things.
- 我需要三样东西 - 什么东西?
What things?
You mean you don't know?
你真不知道?
I was fooling, silly.
我说着玩的,蠢家伙
You need a cigarette because you used to smoke,
你要一支烟,你以前抽又戒掉了
but you quit except when you finish a book.
And you have just one.
除非书写完了,才会抽一根 还要点烟的火柴
And the match is to light it.
And you need one glass of champagne.
而且你要一杯香槟 是法国名牌,唐培里侬
Dom Perignon.
Dom Perignon it is.
是唐培里侬
Annie?
安妮,安妮?
Yes, Paul.
什么事?保罗
I'm almost done.
我快写完了
Oh, Paul, this is so romantic.
噢,保罗,这太浪漫了!
Ian and Winthorne dueling for the right to Misery's hand.
伊恩和温德索恩 为了米瑟丽而进行决斗
Does Ian win? Oh, don't tell me.
是伊恩赢了吗?别说出来 还是温德索恩,是吗?
It's Winthorne, right?
You'll know everything in a minute.
你一会儿就知道了
Get the champagne.
拿香槟来
Oh!
Did I do good?
我做得还好吗?
You did perfect.
你做得好极了
Except for one thing.
只有一件事
This time we'll need two glasses.
这一次 我们要两只杯子
Oh, Paul.
噢,保罗!
Remember, how for all those years,
可记得这些年来,没有人知道 米瑟丽真正的父亲是谁?
nobody knew who Misery's real father was
or if they'd ever be reunited?
或者他们是否曾经重聚?
It's all right here.
全都在这里了
Does she finally marry Ian or will it be Winthorne?
她最后是跟伊恩结婚 还是跟温德索恩?
It's all right here.
也全都在这里了
Paul, you can't!
- 保罗,你不可以的! - 为什么不可以?
Why not? I learned it from you.
我这是从你那儿学来的!
No, no, no! Not Misery!
不! 不! 不! 不要!米瑟丽! 不要毁我的米瑟丽!
Not my Misery!
No! Not my Misery!
不啊!不要毁掉我的米瑟丽!
No!
[PANTING]
[SCREAMING]
我会宰了你 你这说谎的狗日的
I'm gonna kill you, you lying cocksucker!
Here, you want it? You want it? Eat it!
在这里,你要吗?你要吗? 吃掉吧!
Eat it till you choke, you sick, twisted fuck!
吃得噎死你 你这病态反常的混蛋!
[SCREAMING]
[GROANS]
一年半之后
MARCIA: This is it, the very first copy.
J?飞利浦?斯通的 高等教育  作者 保罗?谢尔登  就是这,这是第一本
The word I'm getting is the Times review's gonna be a love letter.
我听说〈时报〉 对这本书的评价不错
That'll be a first.
那倒是第一次
And my contacts at Time and Newsweek tell me they're both raves.
〈时代〉和〈新闻周刊〉的联络人 告诉我说他们两家都极为赞赏
And don't laugh, but for the first time,
不要笑,这还是第一次 而且我觉得你有机会获奖
I think you've got a shot at some prizes.
Great.
那很好
I thought you'd be thrilled.
我还以为你会非常激动 你终于被严肃看待了
You're being taken seriously.
I'm delighted the critics are liking it,
我很高兴评论家喜欢这书 也更希望读者喜欢
and I hope the people like it, too.
But I wrote it for me.
但是,我是为自己写作
Now, don't think I'm completely nuts,
现在,别以为我随口乱说,不过…
but, in some way, Annie Wilkes,
在某些方面,安妮?威尔斯
that whole experience,
那整个经历
helped me.
帮助了我
Paul, since you brought her up,
保罗,既然你提起了她
I have to ask you this or I'll be drummed out of the agents' union.
我得问你,不然我会被工会除名
How would you feel about a non-fiction book
你对将那屋子里的经历写成 纪实作品,有何看法?
about what went on in that house?
Gee, Marcia, if I didn't know you better,
看,玛西娅,如果我不了解你 会以为你是提议
I'd think you were suggesting I dredge up the worst horror of my life
我挖掘生平中最恐怖之经历 就只是为了让我们能赚几个钱
just so we could make a few bucks.
I thought you were over it.
我还以为你已忘记此事
I don't know if anyone could ever
我不知道别人能否 完全忘掉类似的经历
totally get over something like that.
It's weird.
有点奇怪
Even though I know that she's dead,
尽管我知道她早已经死了
I still think about her once in a while.
但我仍然偶尔会想起她
Excuse me.
对不起,我并非有意打扰你 但你是保罗?谢尔登吗?
I don't mean to bother you, but are you Paul Sheldon?
Yes.
是的
I just wanna tell you I'm your number one fan.
我想告诉你,我是你的头号书迷
That's very sweet of you.
你真好
? I'll be seeing you
主  演 詹姆斯?凯恩……保罗?谢尔登 凯西?贝茨………安妮?威尔斯 .
? In all the old familiar places
本片依据斯蒂芬?金 小说《米瑟丽》改编
? That this heart of mine embraces
? All day through
导演  罗伯?莱纳 编剧  威廉姆?高德曼
剧 终 谢谢观赏 .
? In that small cafe
A文字幕gu 帕金森Z夫 .
? The park across the way
? The children's carousel
? The chestnut trees
? The wishin' well
? I'll be seeing you
? In every lovely summer's day
? In every thing that's light and gay
? I'll always think of you that way
? I'll find you
? In the morning sun
? And when the night is new
? I'll be looking at the moon
? But I'll be seeing you
I'll be seeing you
in every lovely summer's day.
in every thing that's light and gay.
I'll always think of you that way.
? I'll find you
? In the morning sun
? And when the night is new
? I'll be looking at the moon
? But I'll be seeing you